

## CONTACT

• Address

Dundee, Scotland

• Phone +447795100884

**⊕** Web

jmcelfatrick@gmail.com www.jonahm.co.uk github.com/Jopo97

## **EDUCATION**

2021

FIRST CLASS BSC (HONS) ETHICAL HACKING

University/College

2017

ADVANCED HIGHERS, HIGHERS, NATIONAL 5

**Madras College** 

## **PRO.SKILLS**

October 2022

Attended The Art of Mac Malware: Detection and Analysis training by Patrick Wardle

December 2020

AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Academy Cloud Foundations

2016

Short Leadership Course by ASDAN (Award Scheme Development and Accreditation Network)

## **Hobbies**

- Gaming
- 3D Printing
- Keeping up to date on computer hardware, software and security.
- Computer building and maintenance
- 1st Dan black belt in Kickboxing
- Reading fictional novels.

# Jonah McElfatrick

Cyber Security Specialist

## **PROFILE**

Solution minded Ethical Hacker. Passionate computer enthusiast with a keen eye for detail. Natural interest in all mathematics and computers. Advanced knowledge of computer hardware, software and network interactions. Experience in computer building and maintenance. Experience working in multiple teams to bring projects together as a team leader. Works efficiently to maintain a high standard of work while keeping up to date with relevant tasks. Able to keep calm and concise under pressure while maintaining work quality and efficiency.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

February 2022 - Present

#### **MALWARE ANALYST - CLAMXAV**

- Analysing software for malware patterns for anti-virus detection rules.
- Creation and implementation of automated malware analysis tools and platforms.
- Creation and implementation of database conversion scripts.
- Daily malware database updates

August 2020 - February 2020

#### **CYBER SECURITY ANALYST - WARACLE**

- Run security and compliance checks in order to provide evidence for compliance standards
- Automating auditing processes in order to increase efficiency.
- Analysing possible security risks within the company and how these can be mediated.
- Managed virus protection systems based on computer virus reports.
- Control and monitor user access and privileges to systems.
- Implemented security response frameworks.

June 2017 - August 2017

#### **SUMMER INTERN - INFORMIT SYSTEMS**

- Worked in a team to solve everyday issues with computer systems.
- Solo project using filemaker to create a new ticketing system for support requests.
- Wiped and disposed of storage devices for secure data erasing.
- Built a server Intel Xeon based server for virtual machine hosting.

### **SKILLS**

- Analysing system security risks to identify and and implement appropriate security countermeasures.
- Web-based Penetration Testing
- Mobile, Network and Desktop Forensics
- Web Development and Deployment
- Windows System Exploitation
- Cloud Development and Security
- Secure Coding Practices
- Keen interest in data encryption and hashing methods
- Basic understanding of machine learning and Al.
- Experience using and automating interactions to a variety of different API's.
- Reverse engineering android applications in order to find security vulnerabilities in the applications code.

#### CODING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS

Python, C++, HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, JavaScript, Google Apps Script Windows and Unix Command Line including bash scripting Windows/Linux/MacOS systems

AWS, Visual Studio, Android Studio, GitHub, Atlassian Suite, Microsoft Suite, G-Suite